* 

 [](https://amaze.org/world-map/)[](#) Toggle Navigation

* About

Attention

X

You are now leaving AMAZE.org.  
Content beyond this site might not be  
appropriate for young adolescents.  

Continue to external site

attentionAttention

X

The following video was not produced by AMAZE.

Play Video

We'd like one thing before you download!

X

Please give us your email address before you download. Feel free to subscribe to our Newsletter while you’re here!

Email 

 Subscribe to our newsletters

Download

is this the thing?

Terms of use
============

Amaze.org Terms of Use
======================

The Amaze partners are pleased to provide the Amaze.org website as an online resource for sexuality and health related information for users 10 to 14 years of age as well as educators and parents of very young adolescents. Amaze is committed to providing honest, accurate information about sexuality and related health issues.

By visiting this site, you agree to comply with the following “Terms of Use.” The “Terms of Use” may be updated or changed at any time. It is important that you periodically review this agreement. Your continued use implies that you accept any and all changes made to this agreement.

If you are having a health or psychological emergency, if you are thinking about hurting yourself or someone else or if someone is hurting you, please get help immediately. Amaze.org does not provide counseling or crisis support, so please speak with a parent, guardian, teacher or other trusted adult or call 9-1-1 or the Hope Center Hotline at 1-800-SUICIDE (1-800-784-2433) if you are in the United States. If you are in the United States and an adult is hurting you in any way, you can call the Child Help National Child Abuse Hotline at 1-800-4-A-CHILD (1-800-422-4453) to get connected with assistance. If you are outside of the United States and an adult is hurting you, [Children International](https://www.children.org/learn-more/contact-us) can help you find a local hotline and resources.

TERMS OF USE
------------

Amaze.org is intended only for users 10 to 14 years of age, educators and parents of very young adolescents.

The information on Amaze.org does not constitute medical, legal or other professional advice. The information presented on this site or sent to you electronically in response to a message from you is meant for general educational purposes only. It is not intended or implied to serve as specific medical advice, diagnosis or treatment. It should never be a substitute for consultation with a physician or other health professional. If you have, or think you might have, a medical problem or symptom, please consult a medical professional right away. [Find a family planning clinic or health center](https://locator.aids.gov/) near you or call 1-800-230-PLAN for the nearest Planned Parenthood health center.

In addition, the information presented on this site or sent to you electronically in response to a message from you does not constitute legal advice. If you have a legal question, always seek the advice of an attorney or other legal professional.

With any information you provide us it is critical that we keep it confidential. When you register and set up your MyAmaze account or subscribe to our newsletter, we ask you for your first name, your username, age, sex, country, zip code and email address. Your other information will be used internally only and to make improvements to the website based on the users that visit. No one else will have access to this information as it is owned and managed by Amaze. We will only use your email address when you indicate you would like something sent to your email address, like the opt-in email lists. We will not use your email address to contact you for any other reason. Nor will we sell or distribute your email address to anyone else.

Your email address will be used initially to send you a confirmation email allowing you to opt-in to Amaze.org’s registration for MyAmaze. Before completing the profile setup process, site visitors will need to confirm their setup via an email opt-in process.

For adult users, a confirmation email will be sent to the user’s email address to confirm the profile setup. After clicking the confirmation link in the email message, the user will confirm and complete the setup of their profile.

For users 10 to 14 years of age, a confirmation email will be sent to the user’s guardian’s email address to confirm the profile setup. After clicking the confirmation link in the email message, the user’s guardian will confirm and complete the setup of the user’s profile.

Amaze does not assume any responsibility or any risk for your use of Amamze.org or the internet. The Amaze.org site does contain links to other sites, but does not necessarily endorse these sites. Amaze does not assume any responsibility or any risk for your use of these sites, their content or privacy practices. Please refer to the individual sites for their “Terms of Use” and/or privacy statements. Once you leave Amaze.org, you may not have the same privacy or other protections.

Amaze, assumes no liability for any diagnosis, treatment, decision or action you take in response to the information that is provided online or sent to you electronically in response to a message from you.

In no event shall Amaze be liable for any injury, loss, claim, damage or any incidental or consequential damages arising either directly or indirectly out of or in any way connected with Amaze.org or any failure or delay in updating or including any materials on Amaze.org, or any use or inability to use any materials on Amaze.org, even if Amaze has been advised of the possibility of such damages.

The entire Amaze.org website is available through the creative commons standards, in a simple and standardized way to give the public permission to share and use our creative work. The materials presented on the website may be downloaded, shared, and/or printed for personal and educational use.

The Amaze partners and staff work very hard to ensure that the information presented on Amaze.org is accurate. However, Amaze disclaims responsibility for any errors or omissions or for unintended technical inaccuracies or typographical errors in the materials.

Amaze cannot and does not guarantee or warrant that files including videos available for downloading through the services will be free of “infections,” “viruses,” and/or “worms” or other code that manifest contaminating or destructive properties. Users are responsible for implementing sufficient procedures and checkpoints to satisfy the particular requirements of accuracy of data input and output, and for maintaining a procedure outside the website for the reconstruction of lost data. Use of the Amaze.org and the internet generally is at the user’s own risk.

These terms and conditions shall be governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of the District of Columbia, USA, and you agree to submit to the personal jurisdiction of the courts of the District of Columbia in connection with any claims or disputes that may arise from your use of the website. In the event that any portion of these terms and conditions is deemed by a court to be invalid, the remaining provisions shall remain in full force and effect. You agree that regardless of any statute or law to the contrary, any claim or cause of action arising out of or related to this website, or the use of this website, must be filed within one year after such claim or cause of action arose and must be filed in a court in Washington, DC, USA.

If you have any questions or comments about the “Terms of Use” outlined above, please contact us at

**Amaze.org**

2000 M Street NW, Suite750

Washington DC, Washington DC 20036

USA

[\[email protected\]](https://amaze.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

_Last Edited on 2016-09-15_

Privacy Policy
==============

It is our goal to respect your online privacy. Your visits to the Amaze.org website remain private and confidential.

### _PLEASE NOTE: This site and the information you send to us is completely confidential. We will only disclose information about you if we are required by law to do so._

This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their ‘Personally Identifiable Information’ (PII) is being used online. PII, as described in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.

### What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our blog, website or app?

When subscribing or registering on our site, you may be asked to enter your email address or other details to help you with your experience.

### When do we collect information?

We collect information from you when you register on our site, subscribe to a newsletter or enter information on our site.

### How do we use your information?

We may use the information we collect from you when you register, sign up for our newsletter, surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways:

* To personalize your experience and to allow us to deliver the type of content and product offerings in which you are most interested.
* To improve our website in order to better serve you.
* To send periodic email updates and newsletters if you opt-in.

### How do we protect your information?

We do not use vulnerability scanning and/or scanning to PCI standards.

We only provide articles and information.

We use regular Malware Scanning.

Your personal information is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. In addition, all sensitive/credit information you supply is encrypted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology.

We implement a variety of security measures when a user enters, submits, or accesses their information to maintain the safety of your personal information.

All transactions are processed through a gateway provider and are not stored or processed on our servers.

### **Do we use ‘cookies’?**

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

### **We use cookies to:**

Compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may also use trusted third-party services that track this information on our behalf.  
You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser settings. Since browser is a little different, look at your browser’s Help Menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.

If you turn cookies off, some features might be disabled. It won’t affect the user’s experience.

### Third-party disclosure

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your Personally Identifiable Information.

### Third-party links

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third-party products or services on our website. These third-party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

Our privacy policy is available as a link on our home page. Our Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’ and can be easily be found on the page specified above.

You will be notified of any Privacy Policy changes:

* On our Privacy Policy Page

You can change your personal information:

* By logging in to your account

### **How does our site handle Do Not Track signals?**

We honor Do Not Track signals and Do Not Track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.

### **Does our site allow third-party behavioral tracking?**

It’s also important to note that we do not allow third-party behavioral tracking

### **COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)**

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under the age of 13 years old, the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, United States’ consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children’s privacy and safety online.

We do not collect information from children under 13

### **Fair Information Practices**

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

### **In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:**

We will notify the users via in-site notification

* Within 7 business days

We also agree to the Individual Redress Principle which requires that individuals have the right to legally pursue enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or government agencies to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

### **CAN SPAM Act**

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.

### **We collect your email address in order to:**

Send information; respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.

### **To be in accordance with CANSPAM, we agree to:**

* Not use false or misleading subjects or email addresses.
* Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters.
* Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly.
* Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email.

### **  
If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can:**

Follow the instructions at the bottom of each email and we will promptly remove you from **ALL** correspondence.

### Contacting Us

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy, you may contact us using the information below.

www.amaze.org

2000 M Street NW, Suite750

Washington DC, Washington DC 20036

USA

[\[email protected\]](https://amaze.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)  
Last Edited on 2016-09-13

COOKIES

We use cookies to ensure that we give the best experience on our web site. You may configure your browser to refuse cookies although some features might not work properly. Read more in our [Terms & Privacy.](https://amaze.org/terms-and-privacy/)

Acknowledge
